

Vladimir Logachev





Fullstack developer, FP enthusiast. Remote (Novosibirsk, Russia)

logachev.dev@ya.ru

Site: https://logachev.dev

GitHub: https://github.com/vladimirlogachev Telegram: https://t.me/vladimirlogachev Twitter: https://twitter.com/logachev_dev

LinkedIn: http://www.linkedin.com/in/vladimirlogachev

Experience

Pamir, frontend developer 05/2020 - 02/2021

Developed a web application, which utilizes server-side rendering and covered it with unit tests. Packaged everything in Docker and set up CI. I also mentored a second frontend developer who joined the team later.

Frontend: TypeScript, React, Next.js, GraphQL, Apollo, FP-TS, Emotion, Jest Infrastructure: Nginx, Docker, GitHub Actions

Eldis, software engineer 10/2019 - 12/2019

http://eldis.ru

I developed a declarative decoder for the internal binary document format, covered it with tests, including property-based testing. Scala, scodec, cats, fs2, decline, specs2, scalacheck

Neolab-Nsk, fullstack developer 01/2019 — 09/2019

https://www.neolab.io

I've implemented new functionality in existing web applications, fixed defects and developed new applications, and microservices, covered them with unit tests and integration tests. Frontend: TypeScript, React, Redux, Saga, RxJS, FP-TS Backend: TypeScript, Node, Redux, Saga, RxJS, Redis, Lua, Mongo, PostgreSQL, Clickhouse, Docker

SocialSweet Inc, frontend developer 08/2018 — 01/2019

Sweet's product is a loyalty platform, social network and online store. I performed tasks related to business logic at the front end and was engaged in covering the existing code with unit tests and tuning them, thanks to which the tests were launched using CI pipeline, and the defects associated with an unsuccessful merging of Git branches in a huge codebase really began to be prevented.

TypeScript, Angular, RxJS

Allmax, frontend developer 11/2017 - 08/2018

https://apps.apple.com/ru/app/savl/id1369912925

I worked in the SavI project — this is a mobile application, wallet with support for 6 cryptocurrencies. I was responsible for the data layer in the mobile application. I applied everything that I learned from books about functional programming and software design, and also completely covered the business logic with tests, as a result of which the application became fault-tolerant and modular, that is, it stopped crashing due to exceptions or unexpected behavior of external services, and allowed to enable and disable support for individual cryptocurrencies at any time. Also inside the company, I made several presentations on functional programming JavaScript, Flow, React Native, Redux, Saga, Ramda, Sanctuary, Socket.io

Other

I organize meetups with practice, code review and FP reading group https://t.me/fpspecialty_ru

Translated Mostly Adequate Guide to Functional Programming in JavaScript into Russian https://github.com/MostlyAdequate/mostly-adequate-guide-ru

About

I see my future in working with functional languages that implement strict static typing. I actively use Scala, Haskell and Elm, but am also ready to take on any other typed functional language, for example: OCaml, Idris, F#, PureScript.

I associate the success in my career with FP, so I will invest a lot of my time and attention in ensuring that FP brings benefits to both companies and individual specialists. I'm ready to regularly explain everything that I understand myself, and to pay time and attention not only to the code, but also to people. I consider pair programming and pair testing to be an effective practice.

Education and courses

Mastering Haskell Programming https://www.udemy.com/certificate/UC-DRMAMOQ5 Packt, 2019

Functional Programming in Haskell, part 2 https://stepik.org/cert/207739 (certificate with distinction) Computer Science Center, 2019

Functional Programming in Haskell, part 1 https://stepik.org/cert/196007 (certificate with distinction) Computer Science Center, 2019

Computer Science Summer School, Theory of Programming Languages Novosibirsk State University, 2019

Maintenance of computer equipment and computer networks Novosibirsk Aviation Technical College, 2004 - 2008